<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Source" icon="./ClearQuest.png">
	<name>IBM Rational ClearQuest Adapter (Offline)</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Reads a data table from a file output right out of IBM Clear Quest application.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node reads a data loaded from a file that has to be generated by 
			IBM Clear Quest application.
			
			To generate a file that may be read you have to follow the steps:
			<ul>
				<li>
					Log in to IBM Rational Clear Quest software
				</li>
				<li>
					Using Clear Quest Navigator list the desired set of Bug Reports
				</li>
				<li>
					Use "Export" option icon located upper right corner of the screen to
					drop down the "Export" menu.
				</li>
				<li>
					Select "Export to an Excel Spreadsheet" option to export Bug Reports (defects)
					to a MS Excel file (*.xls extension) format.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</intro>
		<tab name="ClearQuest Reader Settings">
			<option name="File to read">
				Enter a valid file name. You can also choose a previously
				selected file from the drop-down list, or select a file from
				the &quot;Browse...&quot; dialog. Supported are xls and xlsx file 
				formats.
			</option>
			<option name="Sheet to Read">
	            After selecting a file, you can select the sheet from the
	            available sheets in the file.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Skip Empty Rows or Columns">
	            If empty rows or columns should be removed from the result Data Table,
	            check the appropriate option. 
	        </option>
	        <option name="Evaluation Error Handling">
	            Specify the data that is inserted in a cell with an error. Similar to XLS Reader Node.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Preview">
	            The &quot;Preview&quot; tab shows you the output table with the current
	            settings in the dialog. If the settings are invalid an
	            error message will be displayed in this tab.
	        </option>
	        <option name="File Content">
	            The &quot;File Content&quot; table shows you the content of the
	            currently selected file.
	        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Column Mapping">
			<option name="Mapping">
				A tab that allows user to map columns from the input file to ITS Data Type Format columns.
				
				NOTICE THAT!
				ITS Created column, in the mapped ITS Data Type Format is REQUIRED. Otherwise it is replaced with actual date!
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="ITS">
			Output data compatible with ITS Data Type Format mapped with user-selected columns from input file.
		</outPort>
		<outPort name="Output Table" index="1">Output data with the table structure of the input file.a</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>


