<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./po.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>People and Organization Metric</name>

    <shortDescription>
        People and Organization Metric, ImpressiveCode DePress Plugin Framework.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
            People and Organization Metric quantifies the complexity of a software development in organization. It
            consists of following measures:
            <ul>
                <li>
                    Number of Engineers (NOE) - absolute number of unique engineers who have touched a binary and are
                    still employed by the company.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Number of Ex-Engineers (NOEE) - total number of unique engineers who have touched a binary and have
                    left the company as of the release date of the software system.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Edit Frequency (EF) - total number times the source code, that makes up the binary, was edited.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Depth of Master Ownership (DMO) - determines the level of ownership of the binary depending on the
                    number of edits done.
                    The organization level of the person whose reporting engineers perform more
                    than 75% of the commited changes is deemed as the DMO.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Percentage of Org contributing to development (PO) - the ratio of the number of people reporting at
                    the DMO level owner relative to the Master owner org size.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Level of Organizational Code Ownership (OCO) - the percent of edits from the organization that
                    contains the binary owner or if there is no owner then the organization that made the majority of
                    the edits to that binary.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Overall Organization Ownership (OOW) - the ratio of the percentage of people at the DMO level
                    making
                    edits to a binary relative to total engineers editing the binary.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Organization Intersection Factor (OIF) - measure of the number of different organizations that
                    contribute greater than 10% of edits, as measured at the level of the overall organization
                    owners.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Number of Engineers with Skill X (NOE1 .. NOE2) - total number of edits done by engineers with given
                    skill level(1..5).
                    For example levels could be assign as follows: 1 - trainee, 2 - junior engineer, 3
                    - engineer, 4 - senior engineer, 5 - software achitect or software specialist.
                    (This is an additional
                    PO Metric measure.)
                </li>
            </ul>
            Detail information could be found in original paper:
            <br />
            <a href="http://research.microsoft.com/apps/pubs/default.aspx?id=70535">
                Nachiappan Nagappan , Brendan Murphy , Victor Basili, The influence of organizational structure on
                software quality: an empirical case study, Proceedings of the 30th international conference on
                Software engineering, May 10-18, 2008, Leipzig, Germany
            </a>
            </p>
             <p>
                Please check workflow examples
                <a href="http://impressivecode.github.io/ic-depress/update">here</a>. 
             <br/> 
             Copyright (c) ImpressiveCode, <a href="https://github.com/ImpressiveCode/ic-depress">DePress Project</a>  
            </p>
        </intro>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Engineers data">
            Engineers data has to consist of following collumns: Name (string),
            ExpirienceLevel (Int, 1..5), ExEngineer (Int, 0 - false, otherwise true), Organization (string, organization
            hierarchy could be build by using ';' e.h. A;AB;ABC).
        </inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Change history data">Change history data could be retrived from any Source Repository (e.g. GUT or SVN
            Adapter plugin). It should consist at least from Class (string) and Author (string) collumns.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Metric results">Computed People and Organization Metric.</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
