<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./anon.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Encryption</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Encrypts selected columns from input data set using DES cryptographic algorithm. ImpressiveCode Depress
    </shortDescription>    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Selected columns from input data set, which are plain text, will be encrypted. 
        Selected columns from input data set, which are already encrypted, will be decrypted.
        The same cryptographic key has to be used for encryption and decryption process, because of symmetric cipher algorithm usage (DES).
        Potentially encrypted columns from input data set are marked, so they can be distinguished from plain text columns.
        Output data set has the same structure as input data set - only difference is, that selected columns are encrypted or decrypted.
        </intro>        
        <option name="Column selection">Section, where columns, which will be treated by cryptographic algorithm, can be selected.</option>
        <option name="Exclude">Columns, which will be not treated by cryptographic algorithm.</option>
        <option name="Include">Columns, which will be treated by cryptographic algorithm.</option>
        <option name="Search">Column(s) with given name will be searched in appropriate column set.</option>
        <option name="Select all search hints">All search hints will be automatically selected.</option>
        <option name="Cryptographic key selection">Section, where file with cryptographic key can be selected.</option>
        <option name="Selected file">Path to the file, which contains cryptographic key.</option>
        <option name="Create new and load">File with cryptographic key will be generated automatically and its path will be loaded.</option>
        <option name="Clear">Selected path will be cleared.</option>        
    </fullDescription>    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="In-Port name">Input data set.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Out-Port name">Output data set with selected columns treated by cryptographic algorithm.</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
